鸭子类型，这个很有意思。我一直在说，
Ruby强调的是做什么、对什么方法有反应，
而不是你属于什么类。那问题是，
你为什么要关心这个？是吧？它能怎么刺激生产力？
它能让你重复使用什么？
有些人用了一个非正式的诙谐名称来指代Ruby的这种实现——鸭子类型。
你可能听到过这样一种说法：
如果看起来像鸭子，那它走起来也像鸭子，
叫起来也像鸭子，你也可以像对待鸭子一样对待它。
我的意思是，如果你的对象对某些方法做出反应，
它看上去像什么，你就怎么对待它。
如果它对“give me each of yourself（将你的每一个成分给我）”
或“reverse yourself（自行反转）”做出反应，
在什么东西上讨论这些运算才是有意义的呢？它应该是某种集合。
在Ruby里，如果你说什么东西叫起来像个集合，
那意思是“你可以认为这个东西能对，
大多数相同的，一般的集合比如内置集合的数组可以响应的，
面向集合的方法做出响应。”
如果你在JAVA里用到接口，你就会发现和这个有点类似，
但我觉得这个更容易。
比如说，如果我在我的列表上调用sort，那是什么意思？
假如我的列表就像这个整数型数组，
你可以想像sort在上面运算是什么意思。
如果是字符串列表呢？你可以想像，
Sort在那上面操作、
或是在一个符号(Symbol类)列表上、甚至是从 IO readlines得到的内容上运算，那是什么情形。
从IO readlines得到的是文件中的所有行，一次一行，对吧？
在IO readlines的情况下，我们的意思就是“Sort this file（整理本文件）”。
为什么会起作用呢？为了找出这个答案，我们来介绍一种新的Ruby架构，
它在其他语言中不会出现。
而在它出现的那些语言中，module（模块）这个词
表达的是不同的意思。在Ruby里，模块是指不属于类的方法的集合。
模块不是一个类，你不能对它进行实例化。
不存在模块的实例。
它其实就是一组采集了相关行为并彼此配合的方法。
在一些简单情况下，使用模块
就是采集方法，比如与通用运算集相关的方法，
像是数学运算或本身就是数学运算的常量。
这都是很明显的。我们关注的是更有趣的应用。
更有趣的应用是用模块将方法与类混合。
这是什么意思？
假设，在我声明A类时，
我说“包含某个模块的名称”，这意思是
当我试着对A的实例调用方法时，如果我调用A. Foo，
首先它会搜索A类是否有这个方法，
然后搜索类包括的模块中是否有这个方法，
接下来它的操作我们都已经讲过了。
它会调用method_missing，会指向祖先，
但本质上模块让你有办法说出，
“等等，在这个类里添加点东西，我还没整完呢。”
你之所以想这么做，
是因为相当可能，
比起类和类型来，Ruby更关心响应。
对模块、行为集合的定义方式
是可以在很多不同的类上重复使用的。在学习的过程中，
它会令你吃惊并进一步学习。以上一张幻灯片上的sort方法为例，
你认为它是定义在数组上的，
但事实上不是，
它是定义在叫做Enumerable的模块上的。
只要类知道如何枚举自己的元素，Enumerable模块就可以混合进这样的类。
这个不太明显，所以我再重复一遍。
Let me say that again, because this is a little bit
我们看到了不同的例子。
non -obvious , okay? We saw these different examples of using
我一直在说，我们不是在强行从集合里取东西，
each and I kept saying we are not intrusively reaching into a
我们在友好地跟集合说，
collection and getting stuff, we are asking the collection
“作为交换，请把你的每一个元素给我。
nicely , "Please give me back each element of yourself in turn.
我不管你是怎么得来的，我只想要每一个元素，
I don't care how you get them, I just want each elements so that
那样我就可以操作了。”我们的意思是，
I can do stuff to it ." Now, what we are saying is , "Well , if
“如果你能同意这么做，我知道
you can do that, then there is a bunch of things that I know
如何免费执行一些操作。比如说，
how to do for free . For example, if you can return
如果你能返回自己的每一个元素，我可以对你排序，前提是
each  element of yourself, I can sort you ," great , provided
你的方法...你的集合里的东西可以被排序。
that your methods .. . the things inside your collection are in
我们一会再回来讲这个。
fact sortable . We will come to that in a moment . What else
你还能做什么？如果你能返回自己的每一个元素，
could you do? If you can return every element of yourself , I
我可以用Select、Collect 以及那些我们见过的方法
can test every element against some condition that was Select
来测试每一个元素。这是什么意思呢？
and Collect and those methods that we saw. What does this mean
举了实在点的例子，这意思就是混合就像个合同。
? As a concrete example , it means that a mix-in is like a
我们以Enumerable模块为例，
contract . The module Enumerable, we are going to use it as an
因为它在Ruby里用得很广泛，
example, because it's used all over the place in Ruby , it's
很常用。它假设，在你把模块混合进去的那个类里的目标对象
very common. It assumes that the target object in the class you
知道如何对each做出反应，对吧？
are mixing it into know how to respond to each, right ? Like I
正如我所说，如果你定义一个新类，比如说一个二叉树数据结构，
said, if you define a new class , for example, a binary tree
你把each定义为操作该数据结构里元素的办法，
data structure and you define each as a way to get at the
现在你就可以混合Enumerable模块，
elements of that data structure, you can now mix -in Enumerable
就可以免费得到这些方法。
and you will get these methods for free . It will define for you
它为你定义像all、any、collect、find、include、map和partition这样的谓词，
predicates like all and any, collect , find, include , map,
一大堆很干净利落的谓词，
partition ; a whole bunch of really neat stuff just because you
因为你同意提供each。这是一种超强大的行为。
agreed to provide each . This is a hugely powerful behavior .
Enumerable也是sort在Ruby里被定义的地方，
Enumerable is also where  Sort happens to be defined in Ruby ,
但sort还有其它要求，就是你的模型...
but Sort also has another  requirement, which is that your model
对不起。sort还有其它要求，
. .. sorry . Sort also has another requirement, which is that
就是类...集合中的元素能对
the class .. . the elements in the collection be able to respond
宇宙飞船操作符（）做出反应。还记得宇宙飞船操作符吗？
to the Spaceship operator. Remember the Spaceship operator ?
它把所有等号操作符合成一个。
It's kind of rolling all the equality operators into one. A
如果A比B小，那么AB就是-1，
Spaceship B is negative one if A is less than B. Positive one if
如果B比A大，那么就是+1。如果A比B小，那就是-1，
B is greater than A. Negative one if A is less than B, positive
如果A比B大，那就是+1，如果A等于B，那就是0，对吧？
one if A is greater than B and zero if they are equal , right?
可以想象，不管你想要什么类，
You can imagine for whatever class you want you can define the
你可以定义宇宙飞船操作符，可以定义让它
Spaceship operator. You can define it to be sorting your colors
按你喜欢的顺序对颜色排序。
in your favorite order if you wanted. Now , obviously in classes
在Int和String这样的类中，
like Int and String, Spaceship is already defined with the
显然宇宙飞船操作符已经以你能预见的语义来定义了。这里的重点是，
semantics that you would expect . The important thing about this
如果你有一个集合，这个集合对each作出反应，
is if you have a collection of things and the collection
而集合中的元素对宇宙飞船操作符作出反应，
responds to each and if the elements in the collection respond
那你什么也不用做，排序就能完成，
to Spaceship, then you have to do zero work to get that thing to
对吧？排序是什么？
be sorted, right ? Because what is sorting? It's taking para
就是进行成对比较，看两个中哪个更大，
-wise comparisons and seeing which one is greater of the two,
再以算法型将其重新排列。
and in some algorithmic form put in those things back together
.
In fact there is another module that ships with Ruby called
Comparable, which says , if you provide the Spaceship operator,
which takes one argument , right? Spaceship takes one argument
because there is the receiver of Spaceship and there is the
thing you are comparing the receiver against. If you provide
Spaceship , then I will define these other ones for you and also
give you happy ones like between which tells you if one element
is between two others according to sort order . What does this
all mean? It means the class of objects really doesn't matter
almost at all only the methods to which they respond. Let's look
at a couple of concrete examples of this . Sorting a file, well
, we have File. open, that's a method that returns an IO object
representing an open file . IO objects actually define each.
They define it as, " I am going to return each line of the file
in turn. " That's a pretty sensible semantics for reading a text
file . What does that mean? I can say open a file and sort it .
That's it. I don't have to provide anything because the thing
that I am calling sort on is a collection that responds to each
. It knows how to yield every element of itself . Inside that
collection what is each element? Well , it's a String, right ?
It's a line of a file. Strings know how to compare themselves ,
that's part of the built in String behavior. With no extra work
I can reuse behaviors despite the fact that the classes are
different. I can also say which lines of this file begin with a
vowel , well, that's easy enough . We already know how to use
Select to pass an anonymous method to something ,
anonymous function . For every line of a file we are going to
we are going to pick out the ones where this regular expression returns
true. Again, zero additional work. We can do our own example
with accounts, but before we do that, let's ask how it would be done?